<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UX with Paul</title>
    <description>I&#39;m teaching myself LeanUX, Design Thinking, design ethnography, and frontend coding and sharing the journey here
</description>
    <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://uxwithpaul.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 13:38:11 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 13:38:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Great Messages Come From Exercise number 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve read &lt;a href=&quot;http://copyhackers.com/product/messaging-marketing-messages/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where Stellar Messages Come From&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and perhaps because I’m on holiday in a small village with a poor internet connection right now, it occurred to me that not all of the exercises that I want to do in order to better understand the competitive environment have to be done by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting exercise from the book is to review the kind of content that the people visiting my site are likely to expect, based on industry norms. That’s hardly to say that I should strive to match industry norms, but it’s a useful starting point. You can’t creatively break rules unless you know what the rules are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I know the competition. I could recognize any of their websites from ten meters away. In most cases, I know the founders personally. I know their marketing strategies and their target audiences. I know their feature sets and I know what aspects of their products I envy and which aspects I feel smugly superior about. But now I’m supposed to be focussed on copy, and aside from their names, I can’t recall a thing about how they write about themselves. And yet I’m told, not only by copywriters but by companies like 37Signals, that copy is what sells above all else. Words are what the internet is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I was persuaded to try an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perssist.com&quot;&gt;offshore personal assistant service&lt;/a&gt;, lured by a free offer. Now that I’ve given them my credit card, they’re taking $26 a month from me and I frequently forget that they owe me services for it. Unlike other similar services, they let you roll overpayments to future months, so nothing’s lost as long as you eventually need their help. Well, here’s my chance to get some value from that decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sent them the following task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s my first attempt at describing a task that would be very helpful for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please go to http://limitedwipsociety.ning.com/page/tools where you’ll find a list of all of many online products that compete with mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Visit each of their websites and create a table with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;company name
landing page URL
Main headline
Sub-headline (if there is one)
Text on the main call to action button
Text near the main call to action button&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example this is from the first site on the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Company Name: AgileZen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;URL: agilezen.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Headline: Simple, visual and collaborative project management software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sub-headline: AgileZen helps you and your team get things done quickly, efficiently, and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Button Text: Choose your plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Supporting Button text: none (I did not include “Take the Tour” because it’s not supporting text related to the button. If it said something like “30-day free trial” or “no credit card required” then I would include it. If you’re unsure whether a text is relevant, just include it and I’ll decide if it’s useful for me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If it takes less than an hour, that’s great. If it takes more than an hour, just do as many as you can, starting at the top, and stop after an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went to bed, because waiting for a response from an offshore virtual assistant service can be nerve-wracking. It’s so much more pleasant to make the request in the evening and then be surprised to find the work all done in your sleep, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Elves_and_the_Shoemaker&quot;&gt;Elves and the Shoemaker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I found in the morning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/CompetitorCopy.pdf&quot; alt=&quot;Competitor Copy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/CompetitorCopy.pdf&quot;&gt;Download the PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it very interesting to have all of this text in one place. It’s surprising to see how similar all of the various kanban applications look when you compare the headlines and button texts which are, probably (note to self: this is a testable assumption), all that most visitors read before clicking through for a free trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s hardly enough information to base my own copy decisions upon, but it does suggest that as I’m testing headlines, calls to action, and supporting texts there is a pretty common baseline for comparison. I can now begin to test whether all of the product in my category have figured out the magic formula for conversion-maximizing copy, or if they’re all stuck in rut that I can take advantage of to differentiate my product in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 18:36:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/copywriting/2015/04/06/Where-Great-Messages-Come-From-Exercise-number-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/copywriting/2015/04/06/Where-Great-Messages-Come-From-Exercise-number-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>copywriting</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lean Product Management with Melissa Perri</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/122742946&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/122742946&quot;&gt;Keynote: Melissa Perri - Lean Product Management&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/agilece&quot;&gt;ACE! Conferences&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melissa Perri’s keynote at ACE! last month was a big part of what inspired me to develop my product management skill set. It’s well worth a watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product Management is an art of balancing customer needs with creating business value. Unfortunately; many of the tools and values we have as Product Managers do not focus on building products our customers need; but building what we “think” they will want. In this talk; we’ll look at traditional Product Management; and see how we can adapt Lean processes into the role to create better products for our customers. We’ll rethink our most common tools to better suit a customer focused approach; with plenty of example and real life stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 18:36:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/productmanagement/2015/04/02/Lean-Product-Management-with-Melissa-Perri.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/productmanagement/2015/04/02/Lean-Product-Management-with-Melissa-Perri.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>productmanagement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Reading List for Getting Started in UX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I laid out my learning plan in my &lt;a href=&quot;/general/2015/03/26/Creating-My-UX-Learnin-Plan.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, including growth hacking, copywriting, design thinking, design ethnography, and front-end development. After much searching, here are the books or courses that I’ve decided to use to get started learning what I’ll need to know to become the UX/product manager that &lt;a href=&quot;http://kanbanery.com&quot;&gt;Kanbanery&lt;/a&gt; needs me to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Thinking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Designing-Growth-Thinking-Managers-Publishing/dp/0231158386/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427444930&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=design+thinking&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Designing For Growth Book Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was a no-brainer for me. Jeanne Liedtka and Tim Ogilvie’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Designing-Growth-Thinking-Managers-Publishing/dp/0231158386/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427444930&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=design+thinking&quot;&gt;Designing for Growth&lt;/a&gt; seems to be the go-to book for learning the basics of design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copywriting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://copyhackers.com/shop/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Copywriting Books&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking for something practical, aimed at the kind of work I plan to be doing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://copyhackers.com/shop/&quot;&gt;This series&lt;/a&gt;, by Joanna Weibe, looks like just the thing. I bought the whole series and my plan is to read one book a week, implement its suggestions, and write a book review and share the results of my efforts on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-end Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a long process, and I’m starting simple. My plan is to create a new website for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://aceconf.com/&quot;&gt;annual IT conference&lt;/a&gt; from scratch as a way to practice my skills. To get started in CSS and JavaScript, I’ve bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/1-hour-css/&quot;&gt;these two courses&lt;/a&gt; from Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/1-hour-css/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;One Hour CSS and JS Udemy Courses&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched them both in a morning, doing the exercises along with John. I learned a few things that are helpful, but not enough to get started on any project. To dig deeper, I plan to do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/complete-web-developer-course/&quot;&gt;this more in-depth course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/complete-web-developer-course/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Complete Web Developer Course&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Ethnography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Ethnography-Guide-Private-Sector/dp/1611323908/ref=sr_1_sc_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427446174&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spell&amp;amp;keywords=practical+ethnogrpaphy&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Practical Ethnography&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already read and highly recommend Sam Ladner’s recent book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Ethnography-Guide-Private-Sector/dp/1611323908/ref=sr_1_sc_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427446174&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spell&amp;amp;keywords=practical+ethnogrpaphy&quot;&gt;Practical Ethnography&lt;/a&gt;, which was both inspiring and highly practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/interviewing-users/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interviewing Users&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more advice on talking to users, I’ve also bought Steve Portigal’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/interviewing-users/&quot;&gt;Interviewing Users&lt;/a&gt;. By the way, I highly recommend buying ebooks from &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/&quot;&gt;Rosenfeld Media’s website&lt;/a&gt;, rather than from Amazon. Sure, they don’t get automatically added to your Kindle, but if you buy an ebook from Rosenfeld’s site, you can download it in several formats. I especially like having a PDF format for books with worksheets or exercises that I plan to do at the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/the-user-experience-team-of-one/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The UX Team of One&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ve started reading another Rosenfeld Media book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/the-user-experience-team-of-one/&quot;&gt;The User Experience Team of One&lt;/a&gt; by Leah Buley which I’m finding to be full of really helpful exercises that I plan to do. After a section of introduction to concepts, the book becomes a workbook full of exercises that I can start doing immediately. That’s very appealing, because it means that I can act and add value to &lt;a href=&quot;http://kanbanery.com/&quot;&gt;Kanbanery&lt;/a&gt; while learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also subscribe to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.press.uchicago.edu/ucp/journals/journal/ca.html&quot;&gt;Current Anthropology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1111/(ISSN)1548-1417&quot;&gt;Anthropology of Work Review&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfaa.net/publications/human-organization/&quot;&gt;Human Organization&lt;/a&gt;, just to stay abreast of developments in my field. I’ll admit that I tend to find the research procedures more interesting than the findings, as they give me ideas for structuring my own research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth Hacking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/growth-hacking-lean-marketing-for-startups/#/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Growth Hacking Course&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My introduction to growth hacking comes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/growth-hacking-lean-marketing-for-startups/#/&quot;&gt;these two courses&lt;/a&gt; that I’m working through on Udemy.  Both have helpful insights and I’ll share the results of the experiments that I’ve done and will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sketching-User-Experiences-Interactive-Technologies/dp/0123740371/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427447188&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=sketching+user+experiences&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sketching User Experiences&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Back-Napkin-Expanded-Problems-Pictures/dp/1591842697/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427447240&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=back+of+the+napkin&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Back of the Napkin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rohdesign.com/handbook&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Sketchnote Handbook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can draw! Mike Rhode’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://rohdesign.com/handbook&quot;&gt;The Sketchnote Handbook&lt;/a&gt; looks like a fun and painless introduction to sketching for everyone, and it’s where I’ll start. Other interesting titles include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sketching-User-Experiences-Interactive-Technologies/dp/0123740371/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427447188&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=sketching+user+experiences&quot;&gt;Sketching User Experiences&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Buxton and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Back-Napkin-Expanded-Problems-Pictures/dp/1591842697/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1427447240&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=back+of+the+napkin&quot;&gt;The Back of the Napkin&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Roam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s enough for now. I’d love other recommendations for books and blogs that have been helpful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 18:36:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/ux/2015/03/30/My-reading-list-for-getting-started-in-UX.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/ux/2015/03/30/My-reading-list-for-getting-started-in-UX.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ethnography in Software Design – An Anthropologist’s Point of View with Kelly Moran</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/122543173&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/122543173&quot;&gt;Ethnography in Software Design &amp;ndash; An Anthropologist&amp;rsquo;s Point of View - Kelly Moran&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/agilece&quot;&gt;ACE! Conferences&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethnography claims its roots from the field of anthropology. How can a method used for such a seemingly exotic purpose be useful in the modern world of software design? Revealing and, most importantly, understanding user needs requires sensitivity, empathy, and a disciplined approach – all of which can be found within ethnography. This talk outlines the basic components of an ethnographic perspective, explores a case study from a recent engagement between projekt202 and an accounting software development firm, and highlights how the impact of this research ripples through the software development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a talk that Kelly Moran delivered in Krakow a couple of weeks ago and I found it fun and motivating. I think she does of great job of describing the value that ethnographic tools brought to an IT project that she worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 17:36:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/ethnography/2015/03/27/Ethnography-in-Software-Design-An-Anthropologists-Point-of-View-with-Kelly-Moran.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/ethnography/2015/03/27/Ethnography-in-Software-Design-An-Anthropologists-Point-of-View-with-Kelly-Moran.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ethnography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating My UX Learning Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next year, my goal is to become a competent and perhaps even proficient UX researcher and designer able to generate and implement product design ideas that increase both sales and customer retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are degrees in that these days. People go to university for six years to learn to do that. That fact makes it a bit intimidating. But I’ve reinvented myself many times in my career(s) (chef, event planner, teacher, marketer, sales, operations, balloon artist, juggler, project manager, trainer, and more to come) and I know that there’s a huge gap between academia and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with two people who were very successful self-taught professionals respected in that field. One is a leading design blogger and the other is a successful product manager. So I know it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to becoming an X [insert your dream hob here] is to change your job title to X and then start doing X. Learning follows pretty naturally. Take it from an experienced employer, the biggest difference between a good employee and a bad one isn’t skill or experience, it’s the rare ability to do what you say you’re going to do. An inexperienced X who delivers beats a brilliant one who doesn’t any day of the week. So to be X, just do X, and fake it ’till you make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, the goal should be to learn and develop proficiency through experience as quickly as possible, so let me do a gap analysis here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to start with a brief self-assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Front-end development — I know a little HTML and CSS and almost no JavaScript. My skills in CSS predate HTML5 and my last serious work in front-end code was back in the days of table-based design. So I have a lot of catching up to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copywriting&lt;/strong&gt; — I have a degree in English composition and I used to be a professional journalist. So I can write. However, there’s a lot more to copywriting than being able to write. I need to learn how to choose and use an appropriate voice that makes people feel connected to a brand. I also need to learn how to experiment with copy and learn from my mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphic design&lt;/strong&gt; — I’ve done a bit of design work with Photoshop and Illustrator many years ago, but this is an aspect of the job I’d prefer to leave to experts. My product already has a good look and feel and the design elements are all in place. It’s easy enough to hire people if I need to for specific jobs, so I won’t be devoting a lot of time to working on my skills in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching&lt;/strong&gt; — I’m terrible. I get nervous drawing a tree, and the best thing about trees is that as long as there are leaves on top, it looks like a tree. If I’m going to sketch user experiences as part of my toolkit for communicating ideas to users as part of any collaborative design effort, I’ll need to either improve my sketching skills or get more comfortable with working at my current skill level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewing&lt;/strong&gt; — My experience as a journalist helps only in so far as I am not scared of talking to people. But the actual techniques used in a journalistic interview are all wrong for user research. The journalist isn’t looking for facts or understanding, but for juicy quotes that sell papers. My more limited experience with ethnographic interviewing will be much more useful. In an ethnographic interview, there are three goals: test hypotheses, discover, and bond. Usually an ethnographer is doing all three in what is called a semi-structured interview. Semi-structured in that it has certain research goals and the interviewer will have certain things they want to learn, but it’s also somewhat exploratory in nature and a bit of off-topic wandering can be very revealing and lead to new research goals. So I can do that, but I’ll need some guidance regarding how to do it in a product development context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are some toolkits or schools of thought that I think will be helpful to learn, including design thinking, customer development, leanUX, and lean startup. I’ve read books in most of these areas recently (I’ll list them below) but there’s a huge divide between reading about a technique and applying it. That’s a divide I’ll be crossing in the coming months, and I hope you’ll join me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 17:36:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/general/2015/03/26/Creating-My-UX-Learnin-Plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/general/2015/03/26/Creating-My-UX-Learnin-Plan.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn UX with Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to quickly develop my UX skills because I need to be able to create great experiences for my web users. I’m probably not alone in that. You may be working with a startup that has no UX specialist. You may be working in an enterprise that has no UX specialist. You may be working alone, and you’ve learned that features don’t sell subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently stepped down from my project management role at one of the world’s leading Ruby on Rails web development shops to take the reins of &lt;a href=&quot;http://kanbanery.com/&quot;&gt;one of its products&lt;/a&gt;. Going for me is the fact that the product is already profitable and is one of the most feature-rich products of its kind on the market. Also to my enourmous advantage is that the designer who created the interface is none other than &lt;a href=&quot;http://mariusz.cc/&quot;&gt;Mariusz Ciesla&lt;/a&gt; and he did a brilliant job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not enough. There is a lot of new competition appearing and features alone won’t continue to grow our user base. To do that, I need to learn to connect with them, understand them, and create the kind of experience that doesn’t just meet their needs, but makes their lives better. So much better that they help me to evangelize the product and re-invigorate our slagging sales growth curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not quite starting from point zero. I did a design minor as an undergrad and I have a degree in anthropology and continued to take advanced courses in qualitative research methods during my masters studies. But that was a long time ago. I’m also good at interviewing, but my experience has been limited to journalism and what ethnographic interviewing I’ve done had more to do with “classic” ethnographic scenarios aimed at producing an ethnography, not for driving urgent business decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you can identify — if you need to learn design, user experience, customer development, lean startup, copywriting, and lean UX skills quickly — follow along. I’ll be doing at least one experient each week and sharing here what I read, what I did and what I learned as I set out to become the UX expert that Kanbanery needs me to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 17:36:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://uxwithpaul.com/general/2015/03/24/Learn-UX-with_Me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uxwithpaul.com/general/2015/03/24/Learn-UX-with_Me.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
